[
    {
        "id": "0",
        "question": "What two different ways can scientists can combine elements?",
        "options": [
            "a. Atoms or molecules.",
            "b. Atoms or compounds.",
            "c. Molecules or mixtures.",
            "d. Compounds or mixtures."
        ],
        "correct": "d. Compounds or mixtures."
    },
    {
        "id": "1",
        "question": " In which shell of an atom are the valence electrons located?",
        "options": [
            "a. The outermost.",
            "b. The middle.",
            "c. The second.",
            "d. The first."
        ],
        "correct": "a. The outermost."
    },
    {
        "id": "2",
        "question": "How would you best describes a positive ion?",
        "options": [
            "a. An atom that has an equal number of electrons and protons.",
            "b. An atom that lost an electron and has more protons.",
            "c. An atom that lost a proton and has more electrons.",
            "d. An atom that cannot throw off any protons."
        ],
        "correct": "b. An atom that lost an electron and has more protons."
    },
    {
        "id": "3",
        "question": "What material permits a large number of free electrons to move through it?",
        "options": [
            "a. Conductor.",
            "b. Insulator.",
            "c. Resistor.",
            "d. Ion."
        ],
        "correct": "a. Conductor."
    },
    {
        "id": "4",
        "question": "Which smallest current can be fatal under certain conditions?",
        "options": [
            "a. One-half of 1 amp",
            "b. One-third of 1 amp.",
            "c. One-tenth of 1 amp.",
            "d. One-eighth of 1 amp."
        ],
        "correct": "c. One-tenth of 1 amp."
    },
    {
        "id": "5",
        "question": "What is used to move a sufficient number of electrons to perform a useful job?",
        "options": [
            "a. Heat.",
            "b. Current.",
            "c. Voltage.",
            "d. Inductance."
        ],
        "correct": "c. Voltage."
    },
    {
        "id": "6",
        "question": "How is resistance defined with respect to electricity?",
        "options": [
            "a. The movement of electrons through a conductor.",
            "b. The opposition to voltage in an electrical circuit.",
            "c. The potential difference offered by a material.",
            "d. The opposition to current flow."
        ],
        "correct": "d. The opposition to current flow."
    },
    {
        "id": "7",
        "question": "According to Ohm's law, how much voltage is needed to push one ampere of current through one ohm of resistance?",
        "options": [
            "a. 0.1 volt.",
            "b. 1 volt.",
            "c. 10 volts.",
            "d. 100 volts."
        ],
        "correct": "b. 1 volt."
    },
    {
        "id": "8",
        "question": "What factor normally causes the resistance of a conductor to increase?",
        "options": [
            "a. Decrease in temperature",
            "b. Increase in temperature.",
            "c. Decrease in length.",
            "d. Increase in size."
        ],
        "correct": "b. Increase in temperature."
    },
    {
        "id": "9",
        "question": "What unit of measurement is used to measure electrical power?",
        "options": [
            "a. Watts.",
            "b. Volts.",
            "c. Amps.",
            "d. Ohms."
        ],
        "correct": "a. Watts."
    },
    {
        "id": "10",
        "question": "How much power does a 3-horsepower motor consumes?",
        "options": [
            "a. 0.755 kilowatts (kW).",
            "b. 1.534 kW.",
            "c. 2.238 kW.",
            "d. 2.023 kW."
        ],
        "correct": "c. 2.238 kW."
    },
    {
        "id": "11",
        "question": "When do the magnetic lines of force in a magnet cross?",
        "options": [
            "a. When the north pole of a magnet is placed near the north pole of another magnet.",
            "b. When the south pole of a magnet is placed near the north pole of another magnet.",
            "c. When a permanent magnet and a temporary magnet are put together.",
            "d. Magnetic lines of force never cross each other."
        ],
        "correct": "d. Magnetic lines of force never cross each other."
    },
    {
        "id": "12",
        "question": "How can a polarity be created and the strength of the magnetic lines of force around a conductor be increased?",
        "options": [
            "a. By decreasing current.",
            "b. By increasing resistance.",
            "c. By looping coils close together.",
            "d. By increasing the size of the conductor."
        ],
        "correct": "c. By looping coils close together."
    },
    {
        "id": "13",
        "question": "What methods are the two most common for producing voltage?",
        "options": [
            "a. Chemical and mechanical.",
            "b. Magnetic and mechanical. ",
            "c. Chemical and heat.",
            "d. Magnetic and heat."
        ],
        "correct": "a. Chemical and mechanical."
    },
    {
        "id": "14",
        "question": " What three things are needed to produce voltage by the principle of electromagnetic induction?",
        "options": [
            "a. Coil, core, and current.",
            "b. Magnet, housing, and prime mover.",
            "c. Coil, conductors, and relative motion.",
            "d. Magnetic field, a conductor, and relative motion."
        ],
        "correct": "d. Magnetic field, a conductor, and relative motion."
    },
    {
        "id": "15",
        "question": "What type of current flow is the result of voltages produced by batteries and thermocouples?",
        "options": [
            "a. Direct current.",
            "b. Alternating current.",
            "c. Easily transformed current.",
            "d. Current of no commercial value."
        ],
        "correct": "a. Direct current."
    },
    {
        "id": "16",
        "question": "Which formula is the correct one for finding the resistance of a circuit?",
        "options": [
            "a. Current divided by voltage.",
            "b. Voltage divided by current.",
            "c. Current divided by resistance",
            "d. Voltage divided by resistance"
        ],
        "correct": "b. Voltage divided by current."
    },
    {
        "id": "17",
        "question": "How much resistance of a circuit is applied with voltage of 120 volts and a current flow of 9 amperes?",
        "options": [
            "a. 0.13 ohms.",
            "b. 1.3 ohms.",
            "c. 13.33 ohms.",
            "d. 108 ohms."
        ],
        "correct": "c. 13.33 ohms."
    },
    {
        "id": "18",
        "question": "What ohm measurement is the total resistance of a 5-ohm resistor and a 20-ohm resistor in parallel?",
        "options": [
            "a. 2 ohms.",
            "b. 2.5 ohms.",
            "c. 4 ohms.",
            "d. 5.5 ohms."
        ],
        "correct": "c. 4 ohms."
    },
    {
        "id": "19",
        "question": "What ohm measurement is the total resistance of a 4-ohm resistor, a 10-ohm resistor, and a 12-ohm resistor in parallel?",
        "options": [
            "a. 2.3 ohms.",
            "b. 3.2 ohms.",
            "c. 3.9 ohms.",
            "d. 4.2 ohms."
        ],
        "correct": "a. 2.3 ohms."
    },
    {
        "id": "20",
        "question": " What measurement is the current flow in amperes of a circuit with an applied voltage of 120 volts and a power consumption of 600 watts?",
        "options": [
            "a. 0.5 amperes.",
            "b. 2 amperes.",
            "c. 2.5 amperes.",
            "d. 5 amperes."
        ],
        "correct": "d. 5 amperes."
    },
    {
        "id": "21",
        "question": "What amount of power in watts is consumed by a circuit with 120 volts applied and a resistance of 12 ohms?",
        "options": [
            "a. 10 watts.",
            "b. 12 watts.",
            "c. 1200 watts.",
            "d. 1440 watts."
        ],
        "correct": "c. 1200 watts."
    },
    {
        "id": "22",
        "question": " How many watts of power are present in a 5-ohm unit of resistance in which 2 amperes are flowing?",
        "options": [
            "a. 20 watts.",
            "b. 15 watts.",
            "c. 10 watts.",
            "d. 2.5 watts."
        ],
        "correct": "a. 20 watts."
    },
    {
        "id": "23",
        "question": "What completes an electrical cycle of an alternating current (AC) generator?",
        "options": [
            "a. One positive and two negative alternations in one second.",
            "b. One positive and one negative alternation.",
            "c. One negative alternation.",
            "d. One positive alternation."
        ],
        "correct": "b. One positive and one negative alternation."
    },
    {
        "id": "24",
        "question": "How many rotations per minute (rpm) must a two-pole generator rotate to produce 60 hertz",
        "options": [
            "a. 1,200 rpm.",
            "b. 1,800 rpm.",
            "c. 3,600 rpm.",
            "d. 4,000 rpm."
        ],
        "correct": "c. 3,600 rpm."
    },
    {
        "id": "25",
        "question": "How is the measurement of the apparent power of an alternating current (AC) electrical system expressed?",
        "options": [
            "a. Volt-amperes.",
            "b. Kilovolt-amperes.",
            "c. Millivolt-amperes.",
            "d. Picovolt-amperes."
        ],
        "correct": "b. Kilovolt-amperes."
    },
    {
        "id": "26",
        "question": "What is the capacitance of a 125 microfarads (Î¼F) capacitor when converted to farads?",
        "options": [
            "a. .000125 F.",
            "b. .00125 F.",
            "c. .0125 F.",
            "d. 0.125 F."
        ],
        "correct": "a. .000125 F."
    },
    {
        "id": "27",
        "question": "The rules and equations for direct current (DC) circuits apply to alternating current (AC) circuits having",
        "options": [
            "a. resistive load elements alone",
            "b. reactive load elements alone",
            "c. capacitive load elements alone.",
            "d. resistive and reactive load elements."
        ],
        "correct": "a. resistive load elements alone."
    },
    {
        "id": "28",
        "question": "A 110-volt alternating current (AC) motor records 20 in-line amperes and the in-line wattmeter shows only 1,936 watts being consumed. What would be the power factor of the AC circuit?",
        "options": [
            "a. 80 percent power factor (pf)",
            "b. 83 percent pf.",
            "c. 86 percent pf.",
            "d. 88 percent pf"
        ],
        "correct": "d. 88 percent pf"
    },
    {
        "id": "29",
        "question": "What is the purpose of an electrical generator?",
        "options": [
            "a. Converts mechanical energy to electrical energy.",
            "b. Converts electrical energy to mechanical energy.",
            "c. Converts kinetic energy to electrical energy.",
            "d. Converts kinetic energy to potential energy."
        ],
        "correct": "a. Converts mechanical energy to electrical energy."
    },
    {
        "id": "30",
        "question": "What type of generator has brushes riding on the commutator to carry the current to an external circuit?",
        "options": [
            "a. Universal.",
            "b. Potential type.",
            "c. Direct current type.",
            "d. Alternating current type."
        ],
        "correct": "c. Direct current type."
    },
    {
        "id": "31",
        "question": "What feature is the advantage of having a rotating magnetic field alternator?",
        "options": [
            "a. It requires no slip rings and brushes.",
            "b. Output is taken from the commutator.",
            "c. Output is taken from the stationary stator coils.",
            "d. It requires less power to rotate the magnetic field."
        ],
        "correct": "c. Output is taken from the stationary stator coils."
    },
    {
        "id": "32",
        "question": "The voltage of a primary cell depends on the type of",
        "options": [
            "a. electrolyte and type of cell.",
            "b. cell and type of terminal posts.",
            "c. electrode material and type of cell.",
            "d. electrolyte and the electrode material."
        ],
        "correct": "d. electrolyte and the electrode material."
    },
    {
        "id": "33",
        "question": "Even though the open-circuit voltage of a lead-acid storage battery is approximately 2.2 volts, what number is the normal rating?",
        "options": [
            "a. 2.0.",
            "b. 2.5.",
            "c. 2.7.",
            "d. 2.9."
        ],
        "correct": "a. 2.0."
    },
    {
        "id": "34",
        "question": "A step-up transformer produces a secondary voltage",
        "options": [
            "a. higher and secondary current lower than the voltage and current in the primary. ",
            "b. lower and secondary current higher than the voltage and current in the primary.",
            "c. and current higher than the voltage and current in the primary.",
            "d. and current lower than the voltage and current in the primary."
        ],
        "correct": "a. higher and secondary current lower than the voltage and current in the primary."
    },
    {
        "id": "35",
        "question": "When setting up the bucket truck for rescue, where should you place the strap and how far from the bucket?",
        "options": [
            "a. Lower boom; 10 feet.",
            "b. Lower boom; 15 feet.",
            "c. Upper boom; 10 feet.",
            "d. Upper boom; 15 feet."
        ],
        "correct": "c. Upper boom; 10 feet."
    },
    {
        "id": "36",
        "question": "What two items do you need when setting up the bucket truck for rescue?",
        "options": [
            "a. Handline and a set of rope blocks.",
            "b. Strap and a set of rope blocks.",
            "c. Hot stick and handline.",
            "d. Strap and hot stick."
        ],
        "correct": "b. Strap and a set of rope blocks."
    },
    {
        "id": "37",
        "question": " Which piece of equipment should you use with the manhole guard when using the two-person method of manhole rescue?",
        "options": [
            "a. Handline.",
            "b. Wire hoist.",
            "c. Rope blocks.",
            "d. Windlass handcrank."
        ],
        "correct": "d. Windlass handcrank."
    },
    {
        "id": "38",
        "question": "When rescuing a person from a manhole, your primary concern should be",
        "options": [
            "a. your own safety.",
            "b. the speed of the rescue.",
            "c. the depth of the manhole.",
            "d. not to cause additional injuries."
        ],
        "correct": "a. your own safety."
    },
    {
        "id": "39",
        "question": "What action should you always take when using a two-way radio for line work?",
        "options": [
            "a. Get clearances from the shop",
            "b. Know where other crews are working.",
            "c. Identify yourself on each transmission.",
            "d. Use the electrical shop code on each transmission."
        ],
        "correct": "c. Identify yourself on each transmission."
    },
    {
        "id": "40",
        "question": "Who is responsible for issuing a safe clearance?",
        "options": [
            "a. Craftsman.",
            "b. Crew leader.",
            "c. Superintendent.",
            "d. Base civil engineer."
        ],
        "correct": "c. Superintendent."
    },
    {
        "id": "41",
        "question": "How many year(s) must safe clearance forms be retained after release?",
        "options": [
            "a. Four.",
            "b. Three.",
            "c. Two.",
            "d. One."
        ],
        "correct": "d. One."
    },
    {
        "id": "41",
        "question": "",
        "options": [
            "",
            "",
            "",
            ""
        ],
        "correct": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "42",
        "question": "Which Air Force (AF) form is used to record all blocking and tagging actions done on primary electrical circuits on Air Force installations?",
        "options": [
            "a. AF Form 269, Electrical Facilities Safe Clearance.",
            "b. AF Form 561, BCE Weekly Work Schedule.",
            "c. AF Form 979, Danger Tag.",
            "d. AF Form 980, Caution Tag."
        ],
        "correct": "a. AF Form 269, Electrical Facilities Safe Clearance."
    },
    {
        "id": "43",
        "question": "Why do you use the Air Force (AF) Form 980, Caution Tag?",
        "options": [
            "a. To identify situations out of the ordinary.",
            "b. To control and record all blocking and tagging.",
            "c. To protect the crew working under safe clearance.",
            "d. To record the names of the crew that are doing the task."
        ],
        "correct": "a. To identify situations out of the ordinary."
    },
    {
        "id": "",
        "question": "",
        "options": [
            "",
            "",
            "",
            ""
        ],
        "correct": ""
    }
]